# **Tapas Tripathi**

(C) +358-401916403 |tapas.tripathi.official@gmail.com | Viherkallionkuja 3T 137, Espoo - 02710

#### **SUMMARY**

Committed professional offering around 8 years of experience in analysing and translating business requirements to technical requirements and architecture. Excellent communication skills and a consistent team player in all sorts of environments. Sound knowledge in Salesforce architecture design, Integration and development with sound knowledge on JavaScript frameworks and modern UI/UX developments. Seeking to expand talents by bringing a wealth of expertise to a well-established company.

#### **SKILLS**

- Salesforce Lightning, LWC
- SalesForce UI development, Ajax Toolkit
- Salesforce APEX and Visualforce
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and JQuery
- Salesforce development and design
- · Integrations architecture, REST, SOAP
- CloudSense(CPQ)
- · Copado, Git, Bitbucket, Cumulusci
- Salesforce B2B Commerce Cloud (CloudCraze)

- Robot Framework
- Heroku
- Modern UI/UX development
- Python
- ANT Script
- C, C#, JAVA, JSP, ASP.NET
- Oracle and MYSQL
- Relational database models and SQL, PL-SQL
- · Vlocity Platform Development
- Vlocity CPQ and Order Management

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer-I.
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer-II.
- Salesforce Certified Integration Architecture Designer.
- Salesforce Certified Administrator.
- Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder.
- Vlocity Certified Platform Developer I.
- Vlocity Certified CPQ Developer.
- Vlocity Certified Order Management Developer.
- Salesforce Certified Sharing and Visibility Designer.
- Salesforce certified Javascript Developer I.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Business and Integration Architecture Manager, Accenture Finland, December, 2022 Helsinki, Uusima

Role: Solution Architecture Design Lead, Fennia

**Building Salesforce platform for Insurance client with Salesforce Industries CPQ(Vlocity for Insurance)** 

## Role and Responsibilities:

Break the functional requirements into the technical design with Salesforce Industries CPQ. Taking lead in identifying and mitigating the solution gaps arises. Taking ownership of the performance tuning for the Salesforce system, analyzing and maintaining the life cycle of the product after it goes live as a part of the Products and Offering Team. Development, debugging and prototyping the solutions.

Senior Software Engineer, F-Secure Corporation, August, 2020 - December, 2022 Helsinki, Uusima

Role: Senior Salesforce Developer/Lead, Cloud Protection for Salesforce R&D

# Developing new features for the native security app exchange manage product in Salesforce.

# **Role and Responsibilities (Senior Salesforce Developer):**

Research and develop the app-exchange product with latest salesforce features for the end-customers. Analyse and resolve customer issues related to product and functionalities. Research about new areas for expansion of the product. Designing and developing the microservices for product functionality and maintaining the infrastructure in the cloud platforms. Writing robot automation tests for the newly built functionalities.

Senior Software Engineer, Capgemini Finland Oy, August, 2019 – August, 2020 Helsinki, Uusima

Role: Salesforce and Vlocity CPQ Developer/ Consultant.

# Developing products in Salesforce with Vlocity CPQ and integration to the down systems for Orchestrations. Client: Telia Finland Oyj

This project is all about moving existing product stacks to Salesforce CRM from outdated CRM also releasing new products directly from Salesforce. In salesforce the Vlocity CPQ package is being used to maintain the product behavior where the system connects with fulfillment systems and billing via middleware with the help of Vlocity OM features.

# **Role and Responsibilities (Salesforce and Vlocity Developer & Consultant):**

Requirement analysis, designing the approach using Vlocity and Salesforce, configuring Vlocity rules, Vlocity OmniScript and Dataraptor Designing, impact analysis, development, Unit Testing and Development of the product, analyzing and maintaining the life cycle of the product after it goes live as a part of Products and Offering Team.

Setting up a CI/CD process for development with Salesforce AppExchange product Copado and POC on extended customized features in Lightning Sales Console. Client: Valmet Oy

### **Role and Responsibilities (Salesforce Developer & Consultant):**

This project includes most of the out of the box setup for CI/CD process with BitBucket and Copado(AppExchange Product) and some of the customization to the OOTB features using platform development. We created some apex class and code to imply the business process the customer wanted. Also developed several POC LWC components for Sales Console, by customizing and extending Salesforce Functionalities putting more priority on Sales Rep Experience and performance.

Systems Engineer, TCS - Tata Consultancy Services, September 2015-July, 2019 Helsinki, Uusima

# Customizing B2B Commerce Cloud (CloudCraze) Storefront to integrate business processes. Client: CDK Global Role and Responsibilities (Salesforce Developer & Consultant):

This project includes most of the out of the box setup for B2B commerce cloud, on top of that they had some business process to be incorporated within the application storefront. I customized the Storefront with the help of JQuery, HandleBar.js and Remote actions. Business processes include delivery of a product to different locations for a single order, user activation and deactivation through the Storefront in bulk, setting up a custom approval and delegation process from the Storefront, showing dynamic addendums for the products, legal document generation on agreement of terms and conditions, etc.

# Migration to Salesforce CRM from old outdated one.

# Client: Elisa Oyj

This project is all about moving existing product stacks to Salesforce CRM from outdated Tellus CRM. In salesforce the CloudSense CPQ package is being used to maintain the product behaviour where the system connects with fulfillment systems and billing via middleware with the help of CloudSense Orchestrator.

### Role and Responsibilities (Salesforce Developer & Product Specialist):

Requirement analysis, designing the approach, impact analysis, development, Unit Testing and development of the product, analyzing and maintaining the life cycle of the product after it goes live.

Involved in three different projects under the same client.

## **Ratings System**

# Client: Moody's (US Based Largest Financial Client).

It's a complex project having top notch implementation of high-end technologies with high security. There are a total of five modules for rating systems. We developed modules with the Visualforce page, Lightning Component and apex along with JavaScript, JQuery and Ajax, and implemented data model and backend functionalities involving triggers, workflows, data modelling and database query. I was responsible for developing a whole ICM module on this project, data model and linking it with backend functionality. I got appreciation for developing this complex module from Client. I handled three different instances and modules for this project at the same time.

### Role and Responsibilities (Salesforce Developer):

Requirement analysis, designing the approach, impact analysis, development, Unit Testing and Development.

# **Online Health Insurance Portal (Developing a Salesforce Community Portal)**

# **Client: Cambia Insurance (US Based Insurance Client)**

It's a Customer Community Portal project having high-end implementation of high -end technologies with high security. It's a portal for enrolling in health insurance. There are different types of insurance and each type of insurance carries different costs and includes plenty of benefits. After selecting the insurance user needs to electronically sign an EchoSign agreement document. We developed modules with the Visualforce page in SPA framework using Bootstrap, JQuery, JSON and apex along with Ajax Toolkit, Remote Object and Remote Actions, and implemented data model and backend functionalities involving triggers, integration (Restful) with Adobe EchoSign, email sending, approvals, workflows, data modelling and database query. I was responsible for developing the design of the Page with SPA, data model and linking it with backend functionality. I got appreciation from Client Partner and from the TCS SFDC Practice Team Heads for developing two most critical modules for this project and delivering within the time with zero defects.

# Role and Responsibilities (Salesforce Developer & SPA Framework Designer):

Requirement analysis, designing the approaches, impact analysis, development, Unit Testing and later development of the same functionality using lightning component.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

**GED** 

Narula Institute of Technology, Kolkata WB 2015

B.TECH in Computer Science & Engineering

# WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/tapas-tripathi-242a49b6/
- https://trailhead.salesforce.com/en/me/tapastripathi

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Currently working on the below POC's,

• Data doctor utility- A one stop solution for all your master data synchronization across orgs.

## **HONORS**

- Selected as Vlocity VIP Member by Vlocity.
- Received Applause Award for helping coworkers team and proposing a solution for their complex requirement.
- Received appreciation mails from Cambia Client Partner and TCS SFDC Practice Heads for the quality of work in Cambia project.
- Received appreciation mails and Star of the Year from current project for technical excellence and product analysis.